[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我将至少再一次穿过箭头，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I'm gonna run through the arrows at least one more time,
因为我知道这会让人迷惑，好吗？
cuz I know it can be kind of confusing, all right?
怎么了？
Yes?
&gt；&gt；学生：此时，
&gt;&gt; Student: At this point,
它说的是意义，它印出了生命的意义42？
it said meaning, it's printed out meaning of life 42?
或者说-&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：在四号线运行后，
Or it said- &gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: After line four runs,
我们返回的值出来，它会说生命的意义，冒号，42。
we return the value out, and it would say meaning of life, colon, 42.
&gt；&gt；学生：42，但运行尚未完成。
&gt;&gt; Student: 42, but run is not done yet.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：生成器仍将处于暂停状态。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: The generator would still be in a paused state.
&gt；&gt；学生：是的，对不起，发电机还没有完成。
&gt;&gt; Student: Yeah, sorry, the generator is not done yet.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这实际上提出了一个非常好的观点，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Which actually brings up a really good point,
很高兴你这么问。
I'm glad you asked that.
发电机不必永远完成。
Generators do not have to ever finish.
对你来说，只消耗一部分发电机是完全没问题的。
It's entirely okay for you to only partially consume a generator.
当你不再引用它时，
And then when you have no more reference to it,
它只会像其他值一样被垃圾收集。
it's just gonna get garbage collected like any other value.
好的，所以这样做是完全可以的。
Okay, so it's entirely okay to do that.
事实上，有时你会将你的发电机设计成永远不会完成。
As matter of fact, sometimes you're going to design your generators to never finish.
你知道
You know how
糟糕的是，人们通常会在你的编程中放入一个真正的循环？
bad it is usually looked at to put a while true loop in your programming?
因为虽然真的就像，除非你有一个返回或休息在那里，
Because while true is like, unless you have a return or a break in there,
一阵子真的会永远消失，对吧？
a while true is gonna run forever, right?
实际上，如果你在生成器里面放上一段时间
Actually it turns out if you put a while true inside of a generator and
你有一个产量关键词，
you have a yield keyword in there,
这是一个完全有效的设计，你实际上做得非常普遍。
that's an entirely valid design that you actually do pretty commonly.
我想说的是，生成器正在将while true重新放回编程中。
I like to say that generators are putting the while true back into programming.
对吧？因为你可能想要每隔一段时间
Right? Cuz you might wanna generator that every
一次你调用它，也许While True循环，
single time you call it, maybe the while true loop,
它每次都会生成一个新的唯一ID。
it's going to generate a new unique ID every time.
所以每次我调用下一次，我都会得到一个新的唯一ID，然后它会循环回来
So every time I call next, I get a new Unique ID and then it loops back and
它再次等待，直到我请求另一个值和另一个值。
it waits again till I ask for another value and another value.
这就是对发电机的思考方式，它们的名字来自哪里，
That's thinking of generators in the way that, where their name comes from,
他们正在从外部世界为我们创造或创造价值。
that they are generating or producing values for us from the outside world.
所以这就是考虑发电机是生产者
So that's thinking about a generator is a producer and
接下来我将通过调用dot来消耗它。
I'm going to consume it by calling dot next.
来自异步编程世界，
From the asynchronous programming world,
我已经让你把你的大脑转回另一条路了。
I've asked you to flip your brains back the other way.
所以我要求你们更多地考虑发电机的内部，并且
So I've asked you to think more about the inside of the generator, and
不用担心外面发生了什么。
not worry about what's happening on the outside.
但发电机就是从那里得名的，
But that's where generators get their name,
它们产生一个可以使用的迭代器。
is that they produce an iterator that can be can be consumed.
&gt；&gt；学生2：快速问题，为什么要用圆括号将YOUNT关键字括起来？
&gt;&gt; Student 2: Quick question, why do you put parentheses around the yield keyword?
这有用吗？
Does that do anything?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：语法上它是必需的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Grammatically it's required.
&gt；&gt；学生2：好的。
&gt;&gt; Student 2: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：有一些奇怪的语法围绕着YELD关键字。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: There are some weird grammatic surrounds the yield keyword.
所以，如果你学习ES6语法，就不会有太多的兔子路，
So without getting on too much of a rabbit trail there, if you study the ES6 grammar,
成品率的表达方式，在这个特殊的情况下，它是必需的。
the way yield is expressed, in this particular case it's required.
所以这是一个不幸的语法细微差别。
So that's an unfortunate nuance of grammar.
是啊。
Yes.
&gt；&gt；学生4：有几个问题，
&gt;&gt; Student 4: There's a couple questions there,
请问三号线在等什么？
saying what is line three waiting for?
他以为你提到三号线在等十号线结束。
He thought you mentioned that line three is waiting for ten to finish.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：不，所以让我再看一遍箭头
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: No, so let me run through the arrows again and
看看这能不能回答这个问题。
see if that answers that question.
在第五行之后，没有一个发电机启动。
After line five, none of the generator has started.
我们有一个迭代器，包装在我们调用的Run函数周围。
We have an iterator for it, wrapped around the function we call run.
但它还没有运行。
But it hasn't run yet.
什么都没发生。
Nothing has happened.
我本可以打电话给你的。
I could have called run.
如果这能帮助你更好地理解它，我可以把它叫做步骤。
I could have called it step, if that helps you understand it better.
因为踏步将会一次一个地穿过它，好吗？
Cuz stepping is going to step through it one at a time, okay?
所以我们叫七号线。
So we call line seven.
我们走进它，或者我们开始运行它。
We step into it, or we start the running of it.
我们运行发电机的第一部分，这将把控制权转移到二号线。
We run the first part of the generator and that's gonna transfer control to line two.
第二行开始执行，运行YELD关键字并
Line two starts to execute, runs across a yield keyword and
说，我需要一个值，我要等待。
says, I need a value here, I'm going to wait.
所以我要归还控制权
So I'm gonna return control and
在你准备回答我的问题时暂停一下。
pause myself while you get ready to answer my question.
我会一直等下去。
And I'll wait as long as it takes.
在这种情况下，我们同时有一个答案。
In this case we synchronously have an answer.
我们将发送一个值为10的答案。
We're going to send an answer right back in with the value ten.
所以值10是一个实际的JavaScript数字，它没有什么特别之处，
So the value ten is an actual JavaScript number, there's no specialty to it,
这只是我们传入的一个数字。
it's just a number that we pass in.
可能是字符串，可能是对象，可能是任何东西。
Could've been a string, could have been an object, could have been anything.
但它是我们传入的一个值，现在它被加到1上，x等于11。
But it's a value that we pass in and now it gets added to one and x equals 11.
然后我们转到三号线。
Then we move on to line three.
别被箭头搞糊涂了我们还在运行发电机。
Don't get confused by the arrows we're still running the generator.
我们在三号线。
We're on the line three.
我们开始运行第三行，var y等于1+。
We start to run line three we have var y equals one plus.
哦，还有另一个收益。
And oops, there's another yield.
所以我们需要再次暂停等待控制，所以
So we need to pause again waiting for control, so
我们要把控制权还给八号线。
we are going to return control to line eight.
这意味着第八行将获得一个返回值的对象
Which would mean that line eight would get an object back with value
未在False下定义。
undefined under false.
在后来的某一点上，
At some later point,
与第10行一样，我们将回答挂起的暂停问题。
like line ten, we're going to answer the pending paused question.
第三行的YERENCE关键字正在等待答案，并且
The yield keyword from line three is waiting for an answer, and
我们将通过传入值30来给它答案。
we're going to give it that answer by passing in the value 30.
所以问题的答案是，三号线在等什么，
So the answer to the question is, what is line three waiting on,
它在等待第十行的值30。
it's waiting on the value 30 from line ten.
好的，这个值进来了，30加1，我们现在有31。
Okay, that value comes in, 30 plus 1, we now have 31.
x是11，y是31。
X is 11, y is 31.
我们把这两个加在一起，我们得到第四行的值42。
We add those two together, we get the value 42 on line four.
然后我们输出这个值，42，回到第十行。
And then we yield out that value, 42, back to line ten.
这是一个暂停，继续，暂停，继续。
It's a pause, resume, pause, resume, pause, resume.
每一次停顿都是在问一个问题，每一份简历都在回答这个问题。
And every pause is asking a question and every resume is answering the question.
这说得通吗？
Does that make sense?
是吗？&gt；&gt；学生3：所以我们
Yes? &gt;&gt; Student 3: So we
在四号线暂停了吗？
are paused on line four?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我们目前在第四行暂停。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We're currently paused on line four.
没关系，我们可以把它留在那个状态。
Which is okay, we can leave it in that state.
在第12行，如果您愿意，您可以再次调用Run。
On line 12 you could call run again if you want.
你甚至可以传入一个值，然后它就会进入，然后
And you could even pass in a value and it would go in, and
按照我们编写生成器的方式，我们不会用它做任何事情，但你可以。
the way we've written our generator we don't do anything with it, but you could.
如果你愿意，你可以在第四行半有一个返回关键字
And you can have a return key word on line four and a half if you want and
这将返回值。
that would return a value.
这都是完全有效的，但这不是必需的。
That's all totally valid, but it's not required.
如果需要，可以部分使用此生成器。
You can partially consume this generator if you need to.
&gt；&gt；学生：所以如果你只把y放进去，你就可以
&gt;&gt; Student: So if you just put the y through around then you could just
不断记录生命的意义。
constantly log the meaning of life.
下一步，下一步。
Next, next next, next, next, next.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：是的，没错。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yep, exactly.
&gt；&gt；学生3：在第七行，如果你通过了第一个，
&gt;&gt; Student 3: On line seven if you passed in on the first one,
如果传递初始值，它不会在第二行中断吗？
if you're passing an initial value, would it not break on line two?
&GT；&GT；凯尔·辛普森：不，那不会发生。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: No, that's not what would happen.
这是。
This is one of the.
&gt；&gt；kyle simpson：设计的不是很好的部分。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Not so wonderful parts of the design.
作为VS6，如果将一个值传递给初始点下一个调用，
As a VS6, if you pass in a value to the initial dot next call,
没有等待它的YOUTER关键字。
there is no yield keyword waiting for it.
所以价值就这样消失了。
So that value just goes.
好吗？
Okay?
从外面的角度看这很奇怪。
Which is weird from the outside perspective.
感觉应该有办法抓住它，而且
It feels like there ought to be some way to get a hold of it, and
没有办法得到它。
there is no way to get a hold of it.
包括我在内的许多人提出了对这一矛盾的担忧
Many people including myself brought up concerns about the inconsistency of that
设计怪癖，认为会让人迷惑。
design quirk, thinking that that would confuse people.
有一个建议ES7，一种你可以获得这个价值的方法，
There's a proposal ES7, of a way that you would be able to get access to that value,
而不是通过YORD关键字。
not through a yield keyword.
但在目前的情况下，不要发送值
But at the moment as it stands, don't send a value
到下一个呼叫的第一个点，因为它只是去[噪音]。
to the first dot next call because it's just going to go [NOISE].
这是一个不幸的，奇怪的设计怪癖。
That's an unfortunate, weird quirk of the design.
&gt；&gt；学生2：在第四行，如果你只做x加y的返回，
&gt;&gt; Student 2: On line four, if you just do a return of x plus y,
那不是也结束了吗？
wouldn't that finish also?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：它仍然会做同样的事情。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: It would still do the exact thing.
&gt；&gt；学生2：好的。然后-
&gt;&gt; Student 2: Okay. Then the-
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：但是发电机会
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: But the generator would
完全完整。
be fully complete.
&gt；&gt；学生2：将完成。
&gt;&gt; Student 2: Would be complete.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：是的。&gt；&gt；学生2：好的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yup. &gt;&gt; Student 2: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：完全正确。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's exactly right.
好的，在后面。
Okay, in the back.
&gt；&gt；学生4：他们在聊天中问，在第二行。
&gt;&gt; Student 4: They're asking in the chat, on line two.,
如果这需要很长一段时间才能达到收益，然后您调用Run，但是
if that takes a long time before reaching yield, but then you call run, but
在结束之前调用run，那看起来像什么？
a call to run happens before that finishes, what does that look like?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这对于JavaScript单线程语义是不可能的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's not possible with JavaScript single threaded semantics.
你不可能两次启动发电机，
It's not possible for you to try to start the generator twice,
除非发电机从内部试图调用RUN。
unless the generator from inside of itself tried to call run.
如果你这样做了，你会得到一个错误。
And if you did that you're gonna get an error.
但程序的其他部分不可能再次尝试调用Run。
But it's not possible for some other part of your program to try to call run again.
因为在任何给定的时刻，只有一行JavaScript正在执行，这就是全部
Because at any given moment only one line of JavaScript is executing this is all
基本上仍然是单线程的。
still fundamentally single threaded.
&gt；&gt；学生4：然后他们也在跟进，使用发电机，
&gt;&gt; Student 4: And then they're also following up with, use of a generator,
你能给我们一些现实世界的例子吗？
can you us some real world examples?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我们正在使用异步模式。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We're getting there with the asynchronous pattern.
好的，我要给你们举的真实世界的例子就是这将如何完全
Okay, he real world example I'm going to give you is how this is going to totally
神奇地改变我们所有的异步编程。
magically transform all of our asynchronous programming.
但是除了异步编程之外还有其他用例，
But there are other use cases besides asynchronous programming,
最常见的是产生价值，正如我所说的。
the most common of which is to produce values as I was talking about.
让你的心态回到不担心内心的状态
Flipping your mindset back to not worrying about the inside and
担心外面。
worrying about the outside.
生成器只是生成迭代器的一种方法。
A generator is just a way to produce an iterator.
如果我想迭代一组值，
And if I wanted to iterate through a set of values,
我可以让我的发电机坐在那里，循环，并把这些输出给我。
I could have my generator sit there and loop and yield those out to me.
生成器是迭代对象的一种方式，例如，
A generator is a way to iterate over an object, for example,
我可以有一个对象，它是一个数据结构，
I could have an object that's a data structure,
其中有一堆值，我可以定义一个生成器作为我的迭代器，并且
with a bunch of values in it, and I could define a generator as my iterator, and
只是以某种特殊的方式放弃我所有的价值观。
just yield out all my own values in some special way.
因此，有一些方法可以将生成器用作迭代器生成器。
So there's ways to use generators as iterator producers.
我认为这是它们不那么有趣的用法。
I think that's the less interesting usage of them.
我认为我们正在走向的异步模式
I think the asynchronous pattern that we're heading towards is the more
有趣的用法。
interesting usage.
&gt；&gt；学生：你能让它立即调用来为你做第一个吗？
&gt;&gt; Student: Can you make it immediately invoking to do that first one for you?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：发电机可以是不确定的吗？
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Can a generator be an iffy?
绝对的。
Absolutely.
但是你不会想让发电机成为一个不确定的，除非你把它储存起来
But you're not gonna wanna make a generator an iffy unless you store that
迭代器，因为稍后您将需要该迭代器。
iterator because you're going to need that iterator for later.
所以是的。
So yes.
&gt；&gt；学生4：那么就澄清一下，
&gt;&gt; Student 4: So just kind of clarifying then,
他们说，所以跑道被阻挡直到屈服？
they're saying, so the run is blocked until yield?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：没错。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That is correct.
只有一个标准的老的，
Just that standard old,
在Generato之外，r一切都和JavaScript中的一样。
outside of the generato,r everything's the same as it always was in JavaScript.
单线程。
Single threaded.
当呼叫正在运行时，其他任何东西都无法运行。
When a call's running, nothing else can run.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：唯一改变的是内部发生的事情，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: The only thing that changes is what happens on the inside,
它暂停的能力。
the ability for it to pause.
凯尔·辛普森：好的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Okay.
所以让我们试着多开车，让你的思想建立在内在的基础上，并且
So let's try to drive more, keep your mind set up based on the inside, and
别太担心7号线到11号线的事情。
don't worry so much about the stuff on line seven through 11.
因为那些东西最终会成为隐藏在图书馆里的管道。
Cuz that stuff is gonna end up being plumbing that's hidden away in a library.
我们要关心的是里面的东西
The stuff we're gonna care about is the stuff that's inside of
发电机，好吗？
the generator, okay?